ozbargain.com.au 2017-06-24

# Privacy Policy - OzBargain Wiki

**OzBargain** values our users and is 100% committed to protect your privacy. Since this is a growing website and Internet technologies are constantly evolving, our privacy policy is subject to change and any change will be reflected in this page. OzBargain is not responsible for the content or privacy policy of the websites it links to. 

Registered users: 

Upon registration your 

  * login name (e.g. fred)

  * email address (e.g. fred@example.com)

  * IP address (e.g. 101.234.75.20)

are collected and are required to use OzBargain 

Optionally, you may enter information into your profile which is located in My Account-Edit-Profile. 

  * gender (e.g. male)

  * twitterid (e.g. ozbargainbuzz)

  *   * Signin with Google+ or Facebook 

    * Facebook: public profile, friend list and email address

    * Google+: public profile, email address

Guests (non-registered users): 

OzBargain doesn't collect any personal data for visitors. 

Viewable by the Public: 

  * login name 

  * gender (e.g. male)

  * twitterid (e.g. ozbargainbuzz)

  * 

[Moderators & Admins](https://www.ozbargain.com.au/wiki/help:moderators "https://www.ozbargain.com.au/wiki/help:moderators") : 

  * email address 

  * IP address

  * Signin with Google+ or Facebook 

  * login name - To publicly identify and differentiate users who post, comment, and vote on OzBargain. 

  * gender - To publicly identify whether the user is a male or female.

  * twitterid - To publicly identify the 

URL

of a selected Twitter page.

  * Website 

URL

\- To publicly identify the 

URL

of a selected 

URL

.

  * email address - are used in order for OzBargain to: 

    * confirm account is associated with an email address through confirmation email.

    * send optional daily newsletter.

    * send notifications of new comments, subscriptions, and private messages.

  * ip address -

    * used to cross reference with external SPAM lists and internal block lists (e.g. block SPAMMERS).

    * used to audit votes, comments, and deal posts in order to enable transparent posting (e.g. companies pretending to be customers)

    * used for analysis of your visits to OzBargain.

  * User inputted information (e.g. email address)

  * Server logged information (e.g. IP address)

  * Cookies

## What do our cookies do?

Cookies are a small text file that is transferred to your hard drive or the internal memory of your mobile device. Websites use cookies to make the browsing experience more efficient, and to help you use websites to their full potential. 

They help you to personalise your experience with our site, allowing you to engage with the OzBargain community fully. Our cookies enable you to vote, comment, and stay signed in while you browse the site. 

They ensure your sign up process is as efficient as possible, we use cookies as a way to authenticate you as a registered user, allowing you to fully personalise your user profile and settings. 

## How are 3rd party cookies used on OzBargain?

Third parties may be placing and reading cookies on your browser, or using web beacons to collect information, in the course of ads being served on OzBargain. 

Google, in particular, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on OzBargain. Google's use of the DART cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html "http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html"). 

## Use of Information

We will only use the information you have provided lawfully. Under no circumstances will any of your personal information be passed on or sold to any third party, at any time. All information collected is kept securely on our servers and backups to protect against loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at this website. 

Personal information is stored and transferred on servers located in Australia & the USA. 

## How to view or correct your personal information?

Users can view personal information about their account by logging into OzBargain and navigating to My Account. Users can change their personal details such as their username or email address within the My Account settings. (Username changes are permitted once every 12 months only). 

Upon request, we can provide a database dump of all of your personal details as well as collected information such as IP addresses. Please note that this process can take up to 30 days. A user may request this by [contacting us directly](https://www.ozbargain.com.au/contact "https://www.ozbargain.com.au/contact"). 

## Handling a privacy complaint

Complaints about a privacy issue can be made by making a request in the [Talk with a Moderator forum](https://www.ozbargain.com.au/forum/10041 "https://www.ozbargain.com.au/forum/10041") or by [contacting us directly](https://www.ozbargain.com.au/contact "https://www.ozbargain.com.au/contact"). Moderators & staff will discuss the issue and work on a resolution with the user in a reasonable timeframe. 

Last edited by **moocher** on 2016/02/17 15:53
